Welcome back
Today we are going to play a new pack called The Winter Rescue
Once again we find ourselves in a custom spawn
which looks like a crushed shuttle
And, before we even open the quest book for some lore, the lore found us
And this time it is not just a wall of text
but a whole sequence of images
We could skip this
but I think it looks cool and it deserves to be shown
So slow down the video if you want more immersion
And finally we survived
I mean, not only from the rocket crush
but also from the long introduction
And now our adventure shall begin
After finding a way out of that wrecked ship
we start collecting the basic materials
The first thing we look for is gravel
which is found underneath the Oxide Daisy flower
Then we gather some sticks from some bushes
And with the help of a rudimentary flint knife
We can also take some vines out of those leaves
But, to do anything more complex, we will need a crafting table
And this one works within world item placement
So, we fill in the grid
and then we complete the crafting with a process knife
And the first thing we craft is a drying rack
so that we can get some straw from the vines we collected earlier on
With that, we can make some rope
which we can use to craft our first tools
Now that we have a pickaxe
we can spend the rest of the night collecting stone
which, as expected, comes in different variants
And after a long night, finally day is coming
Since the weather forecast is good
we can go outside and plow some snow
collect some wood and a bunch of other materials
Since we are getting cold and it's getting dark again
We craft a campfire for our next night
We throw some fuel inside it and then pitch it on fire
This can also be used to light some sticks on fire, making torches
But this is not the only thing we can do with fire
We can also make Pottery Kilns
And the first one shall be used to smooth some stone
The first usage we have for stone is a tree stump
which we can use to chop down tree lumbers into planks
or to hammer stone into slabs
With those we can finally make our first chest
Which, as you can tell by our inability to pick it up, was really needed
After cleaning our inventory
we smash some flux out of some sedimentary stone
Next, we fire that up to get some quicklime
Meanwhile, we prepare some clay buckets
and fire those into ceramic buckets
Now we can fill a barrel with water and dissolve some quicklime in it
Finally, we add some sand to make mortar
And it was then that a storm caught us unprepared
If we go outside, we can barely see anything
and the temperature reached -60 degrees
Before freezing to death, we go back to our campfire to warm up
And then we go back to processing some bricks
which will be part of our future bloomery
For that, we are also going to need some copper and some treated wood
Looking for new resources right now is an issue since there is a storm ongoing
so we work with what we have
Luckily we have enough materials to get a creosote funnel and some piles of logs to char
We place the funnel on the bottom of a pile of logs
and then we ignite the thing as if we were on Terra Firma
After waiting not too much time, the process is complete and we can gather some charcoal
But, what we were looking for at the moment was the leftover creosote oil
Which we use to seal some wood planks
Those are used to craft bellows
But it looks like we also need some leather for that
Luckily the storm is now gone
So we can go outside and hunt some walking leather
But that's not ready yet
We have to first clean it up from all of the fur it had
Now that we have our bellows, we only need a couple of copper ingots
Since the weather is now good, we can go outside and look for some copper
Which luckily wasn't too hard to find
The issue is turning that into a sheet
We start by panning the raw malachite ore out of the gravel
We put that in a clay jar with some charcoal
After firing it up, we can break the jar to retrieve our copper
To make a plate we just put our cold ingots on a wood anvil and smash with our hammer
No need for tedious minigames
With that, we can now craft our tuyere
However, it looks like there's something else we have to do before we can get our bloomery
The first thing is a Research Station
so we can unlock the crafting recipe of the machine
But, even if we did that, we would have no materials to work inside it
So, instead of researching the bloomery
Our first research shall be some tools that will help us find some raw minerals to work
And, after committing some stone to that research
We find the missing clues in a copper ingot
Now we have the required knowledge to craft a prospector pick
And the first thing we found is lignite
Usually that's the most useless kind of fuel, but here it can be converted into coal
But that's still not the mineral we need for our progression
So, to have an easier time finding some iron, we research even better prospecting tools
But this time, we also have to do some paperwork
Since we don't have access to paper yet
We shall use a stone plate and some charcoals to draw our schemes
And now we have a new research minigame to figure out
And it looks like we just have to pick matching pairs of items
So, after quickly doing all the paperwork, we need one more clue, a prospector pick
With that, we now have our Prospector Core Spade, which will be way more helpful
And, after some more exploration and prospecting, we found some iron-rich minerals
But, before reaching iron
we gather some tin and some more copper to make some bronze for a better pickaxe
With that, we gather some magnetite which was also required to start the bloomery research
We quickly do the research minigame
And examine some stuff
Thus finishing the research which allows us to build our bloomery
Once the structure is in place, we fill it with magnetite and charcoal
Then we pitch it on fire and blow air on it
Once the process is completed and the fire is out, we gather our iron
With that we can now move on to the steam age
where we can finally unlock a normal crafting table
And our rewards is more chunk claims
which remind us that we should stop for a moment to build a proper base
But, before that, we shall get some more quality of life, such as snowshoes
And we must not forget to add some insulating straw to our clothing
With our new shoes, we can run to our new shelter, made out of packed snow
Here we can have a nice room
with all of our stuff and also an Alloy Kiln, which will make melting stuff easier
This is nice and all, but we should also worry about food
The rations we savaged from our ships are running out
so we need something to put in our new pot
During our expedition, we found some frozen stuff which we can defrost on our campfire
And, with that, we now have some seeds to plant
But not all of those plants can grow in this climate
But some do, so we shall have a diet based on rye and turnips
And we can integrate with some extra stuff
such as mushrooms, which we can grow on our armor with our body heat
With all of that stuff we can make a nice stew
But we will also need something to drink
And the water in this place is all dirty and cold
So we boil it
But that was not a balanced enough diet
And since we are all so mentally exhausted and out of inspiration
We take an opportunity on this sunny day to go and do some outside activities
Such as placing a campfire on an iced lake
We take off our clothes and then we take a nice refreshing bath
And here we also found a source of proteins, some kelps
and also some ruins of an ancient civilization
But we can't keep the breath for long enough to explore those ruins
and we are also getting cold
So, we dry out the campfire, put on our dress and go back to the millstone
And looking at that thing spin gave us some inspiration for something even more spinny, a mixer
And with that we can mix up some fire clay, which we can use for a Blast Furnace
But there is something else that moves up and down, a forge hammer
This will allow us to convert 3 ingots to 2 plates
Giving us the first upgrade from hammering ingots on our wood anvil
However, working that thing by hand is quite hard and slow
So we start working on a way to not have to manually crank those heavy machinery
But it looks like we can't fit those schematics in our stone tablets
So we start working on something to help us with our research
And after a lot of more manual work, we manage to get some proper paper
Then we get some ink
And, with those new tools, we can finally get into researching more complex stuff
And, after an intensive studying session
we manage to fully understand how steam engines work
We studied so intensively that we also crafted one in the meantime
And since crafting more is going to be problematic, we have to use it properly
We start by laying down a burning box with a boiler
Then we add a pump and manually crank it to fill the boiler with water
Finally, we add the engine with its flywheel
Now we just add some fuel and our machine will start working
And to increase its strength we can add a pump
Which, of course, can be pushed by the engine
And we can watch our forge hammer work faster
But what we really need that power for is crafting bigger things
such as a Mechanical Calculator
And that is one quite heavy machine
And from that machine we get research points
Which are now starting to become required to complete our research
And with those points we now unlock ore doubling
But this room is crammed and we are already rebuilding stuff too often
So we made a new room where we can keep all of our machinery
To use them, we fuel our boiler
then we manually crank the pumps until the engine starts spinning
Once it gets some traction, we engage the gears that will connect the pumps to the engine
And now we have leftover power to turn on our workshop machinery
And the machines are now going to work way faster than we were manually cranking
And work more efficiently with the better gear ratios
But making that workshop was not easy
We run into many difficulties
Starting from the diseases caused by our poor diet
So we made an incubator
where we start cultivating bacteria to make weird stuff
that resemble chocolate that we can integrate in our diet
But that's not the only thing we made
We also set up some fish traps to get some real proteins and also some plant oil
And to keep warm underwater we can use this handy Hand Stove
And to finish our quality of life improvements
We also have a new water filter where we can refill our new thermos
But, to truly fix our issues
We will need to start cultivating a higher variety of plants
The main issue is that they won't grow on snow
And the dirt bellow is too icy to grow those crops
So, to warm up the ground in a large area
We retrieved the core of our ship and used it to build a Large Heat Generator
And while this will make the soil more fertile
It will also burn a lot of fuel
But what matters is that we can now grow wheat
Once we have some, we can crush it into flour
That we can use for make dough
But eating that is not healthy
So we add some lime dye to make slime balls
And with those we can make some glue
Which means that we can now make contraptions
And thus we have automated the fuel production
You probably notice how slow it's working
And that's because we wanted to keep some of our power producing for the rest of the workshop
But that was still not enough, so we doubled our capacity by moving to the cast iron tier
And most of that power is going inside our new dynamo which will produce some electricity
Which we can use to finally obtain some steel
And to make the process go smoother, we shall use our new assembly line to make our first capacitor
For the next task we are going back in our greening garden
Where we tap some latex from a (?) tree
We mix that with some sulfur to make vulcanized rubber
Which we can use to finally unlock mechanical belts
Finally, to complete the steam age tier, we quickly craft our first circuitry
And we shall use our first circuit for a simple electrolyzer
Which of course is going to electrolyze water, or more precisely salt water to get sodium hydroxide
And I guess the leftover gases are vented
Anyways, we wash up some bauxite
and then we mix it with sodium hydroxide to extract aluminium hydroxide
We blast it with lava heat to get aluminium oxide
But to extract aluminium from that we are going to need some cryolite
Which is going to be just a few more chemical steps
After quickly doing those things, we are ready to cook our first aluminium ingot
And getting there was a GrogTech tier-worthy experience
Now that we are on fire, we do not want to go back to RF machinery
So we look into a more complex Heat Generator
Since to complete our research in conventional ways we would need too many expensive blocks
We instead opt for fueling our research with expensive but easy-to-find coal
And there we have our tier-2 generator
The upgrade consists in a tank for fluids
We can add steam to increase the range and heating our water to power a heat pipe
And the first thing we shall do with that extra heat is feed a steam charger
to fill our new heater vest
With that thing equipped, not even a blizzard can stop us
And after fooling around the whole night with our hot drinks, a hot sauna is what we need
That gave us a lot of inspiration, so much that we realized that
Instead of wasting steam like that, we can instead feed it to a Compact Steam Engine
Which we can use to self-power our farm
and have even more leftover fuel for our workshop
Which is now equipped with a Bending Machine that can make plates, rods and wires
And now we can make a big enough batch of circuits and motors
We have motors. We have circuits. We have servo cores
Which means we can now unlock many new machines
However, with those upgrades, our factory has now hit the current end of our adventure
But fear not, we will come back when the new materials and generators will be released
Bye bye
欢迎回来
今天我们来玩一个叫《冬季救援》的新整合包
再一次地 我们发现自己身处一个自定义出生点
看起来像是一艘坠毁的飞船
我们还没来得及打开任务书看故事 故事倒先找上门来了
这次还不只是一面墙的文字
而是一连串的图片
我们可以跳过
但我觉得它看起来很酷 值得展示一下
所以如果你想更沉浸的话可以把视频慢放
终于我们活了下来
我是说 不仅是从火箭坠毁中活下来
也是从漫长的开场中活下来
现在 我们的冒险开始了
从飞船残骸里找到出路之后
我们开始收集基础材料
我们首先要找的是沙砾
它就在（氧化雏菊花？需要查游戏内翻译 我把不确定的都括起来）下面
然后我们从灌木丛里采集一些木棍
借助一把简陋的燧石刀
我们还可以从那些树叶中取下一些藤蔓
但是 要做更复杂的事情 我们需要一个工作台
这个工作台是通过直接放置物品来合成的
所以 我们把物品放在格子里
然后用加工刀完成合成
我们合成的第一个东西是（晾干架）
这样就能从之前收集的藤蔓那里得到一些（干草？）
有了（干草？）我们就可以做绳子
用来合成我们的第一批工具
现在我们有了镐子
就可以把剩下的夜晚时间用来挖石头
不出所料 石头有多种不同的变种
经过了一个漫长的夜晚 白天终于来了
既然天气不错
我们可以出去铲铲雪
收集一些木头和一堆其它材料
由于我们感觉有点冷 而且天也快黑了
所以我们合成了一个篝火来对付下一个夜晚
我们往里面扔些燃料 然后把它点燃
这也可以用来点燃一些木棍 做成火把
但火能做的还不止这些
我们还可以做（陶窑？）
第一件陶器用于打磨一些石头
我们做的第一个石器是树桩
可以用来把原木劈成木板
或者把石头砸成半砖
有了这些 我们终于可以做出第一个箱子了
从我们捡不起来它就能看出 这个箱子确实非常需要
清理完物品栏之后
我们把一些沉积岩敲碎来获取熔剂
接下来 我们把它烧一下来获得生石灰
同时 我们准备一些黏土桶
把它们烧成陶瓷桶
现在我们可以在木桶里装上水 并在里面溶解一些生石灰
最后 我们加入一些沙子来制作（砂浆？）
就在这时 一场暴风雪让我们措手不及
走到外面几乎什么都看不见
温度降到了零下 60 度
在冻死之前 我们回到篝火旁暖暖身子
然后我们回去加工一些砖块
这些砖块将是我们未来（炼铁炉？）的一部分
为此 我们还需要一些铜和一些处理过的木材
眼下因为暴风雪还在继续 寻找新资源是个问题
所以我们用手头现有的东西来应付
幸运的是 我们有足够的材料做一个（杂酚油漏斗？）和几堆待烧制的原木
我们把漏斗放在原木堆的底部
然后像在群峦传说里一样点燃这个东西
没过多久烧制就完成了 我们可以收集一些木炭
但是 我们当时真正想要的是剩余的杂酚油
我们用杂酚油来密封一些木板
这些用来合成风箱
但看起来我们还需要一些皮革
幸运的是暴风雪已经过去了
所以我们可以出去猎一些会走的皮革
但它还需要一些处理
我们得先把上面的毛清理干净
现在我们有了风箱 只需要几个铜锭就行了
既然现在天气不错 我们可以出去找一些铜
幸运的是铜并不难找
问题在于如何把它做成板
我们先从沙砾中淘洗出孔雀石粗矿
把它和一些木炭一起放进黏土罐里
烧制之后 我们打碎罐子取出铜
要做成板 我们只需要把冷锭放在（木砧？）上用锤子砸
而无需繁琐的小游戏
有了它 我们现在可以合成（鼓风口？）了
不过 看起来在做出炼铁炉之前我们还有些其他的事情要做
首先是研究站
这样我们才能解锁这台机器的合成配方
但即便我们解锁了 也没有材料来制作它
所以 与其研究炼铁炉
我们优先研究的对象应该是一些能帮我们找到原矿的工具
而且 在投入了一些石头用于研究之后
我们在一个铜锭中找到了缺失的线索
现在我们有了合成探矿镐所需要的知识
我们找到的第一样东西是褐煤
通常这是最没用的燃料 但在这里它可以转化成煤
但这还不是我们发展所需要的矿物
所以 为了更容易找到铁 我们研究更好的探矿工具
但这次 我们还要做一些文字工作
因为我们还没有纸
我们得用石板和一些木炭来画图纸
现在我们要弄清楚一个新的研究小游戏
看起来我们只需要找出成对的物品就行了
所以 在快速完成所有文字工作之后 我们还需要一条线索 一把探矿镐
有了它 我们现在有了有用得多的（探矿铲？）
而且 在经过更多的探索和探矿之后 我们发现了一些富含铁的矿物
但是在真正做出铁之前
我们先收集一些锡和更多铜来制作青铜来做一把更好的镐
有了它 我们收集了一些开始炼铁炉研究所需要的磁铁矿
我们快速完成了研究小游戏
然后检查了一些东西
这样就完成了研究 使我们能够建造炼铁炉
结构就位之后 我们在里面填入磁铁矿和木炭
然后将其点燃并吹入空气
过程完成后火灭了 我们就收集到了铁
有了它 我们现在可以进入蒸汽时代
终于能解锁正常的工作台了
而我们的奖励是认领更多的区块
这倒是提醒我们应该停下来建一个像样的基地了
但是在那之前 我们得搞些提升生活品质的东西 比如雪鞋
也别忘了往衣服里塞一些保温稻草
穿上新鞋子 我们可以跑向我们用（压实雪？）做的新庇护所了
我们可以在这里建一个不错的房间
放上我们所有的东西和一个让熔炼东西更容易的（合金窑？）
这里不错是没错 但我们也应该担心食物问题
我们从飞船搜刮的口粮快吃完了
所以我们需要一些能放进新锅里的东西
在探险中 我们找到了一些冻住的东西 可以在篝火上解冻
这样 我们现在就有一些种子可以种了
但不是所有植物都能在这种气候下生长
但有一些可以 所以我们的饮食将以黑麦和芜菁为主
我们还可以用一些额外的东西来补充
比如蘑菇 我们可以利用体温在盔甲上种植它们
有了这些东西 我们可以做一锅好吃的炖菜
但我们还需要一些喝的
而这个地方的水又脏又冷
所以我们把它烧开
但这样的饮食还不够均衡
而且因为我们都精神疲惫 毫无灵感
我们趁着这个晴天出去做一些户外活动
比如在结冰的湖面上放一个篝火
我们脱下衣服 享受一个清爽的澡
在这里我们还找到了蛋白质来源——一些海带
以及一些远古文明的废墟
但我们憋气的时间不够去探索那些废墟
而且我们也开始冷了
所以 我们通过篝火把自己弄干 穿上衣服 回到（磨石？）那边
看着那个东西旋转给了我们一些灵感 做个更转的东西——搅拌机
有了它 我们可以混合一些耐火黏土 用来做高炉
但还有一个东西能做上下运动——锻造锤
它让我们能够把 3 个锭变成 2 个板
这是相较于在木砧上锤锭的第一个升级
但是 用手来操作这个东西相当困难而且很慢
所以我们开始想办法 不用手动摇这些重型机械
但看起来这些图纸塞不进我们的石板
所以我们开始做一些能帮助研究的东西
经过大量的手工劳动之后 我们终于搞到了一些正确的纸
然后我们搞了些墨水
有了这些新工具 我们终于可以开始研究更复杂的东西了
经过一次高强度的学习之后
我们完全搞懂了蒸汽引擎的工作原理
我们学得太投入了 顺带还合成了一台
而且因为合成更多太困难了 我们必须正确使用它
我们先放下一个燃烧室和锅炉
然后我们加一个水泵 手动摇它来把锅炉装满水
最后 我们把引擎和它的飞轮装上
现在我们只要加点燃料 机器就开始运转了
为了增加动力 我们可以加一个水泵
当然 这个水泵可以由引擎驱动
我们可以看到我们的锻造锤工作得更快了
但我们真正需要这些动力去合成更大的东西
比如机械计算器
这可是一台相当重的机器
我们可以从这台机器得到研究点数
从现在开始我们需要这些点数来完成研究
有了这些点数 我们解锁了矿物增产
但这个房间太拥挤 我们太频繁地重建东西了
所以我们做了一个新房间 可以放所有的机械设备
要使用它们 我们先给锅炉添加燃料
然后手动摇动水泵直到引擎开始旋转
一旦有了牵引力 我们就接上齿轮把水泵连接到引擎上
现在我们有剩余的动力来启动车间机械了
这些机器现在的运行速度比我们手摇时快多了
而且通过更好的齿轮比 效率也更高了
但打造那个车间并不容易
我们遇到了很多困难
首先是糟糕饮食引发的疾病
所以我们做了一个培养箱
开始培养细菌来制造奇怪东西
作为可以纳入食谱的巧克力类似物
但我们做的不止这些
我们还设置了一些捕鱼笼来获取真正的蛋白质和一些植物油
为了在水下保暖 我们可以用这个（便携手炉？）
为了完成我们的生活质量提升用品
我们还做了一个新的滤水器 可以给新保温瓶装水
但是 要真正解决我们的问题
我们需要开始种植更多种类的植物
主要的问题是它们不能在雪上生长
而下面的泥土太冰了 种不了那些作物
所以 为了给一大片区域的地面升温
我们取回了飞船的核心 用它造了一个（大型热力发生器？）
虽然这会让土壤更肥沃
但它也会消耗大量燃料
不过重要的是我们现在能种小麦了
有了小麦 我们可以把它磨成面粉
用来做面团
但光吃那个不健康
所以我们在里面加了些黄绿色染料来做出黏液球
有了那些我们可以做胶水
这意味着我们现在可以制造机械装置了
这样我们就自动化了燃料生产
你可能注意到它运行得很慢
那是因为我们想把一部分动力留给车间的其它部分
但那还不够 所以我们升级到铸铁等级 把产能翻倍了
大部分动力会输送到我们新的发电机里
我们总算可以用电来获得钢了
为了让过程更顺畅 我们用新的装配线来制作第一个电容
下一个任务 我们回到我们的温室花园
在那里我们从一棵（？）树上采集乳胶
我们把它和一些硫混合来制作硫化橡胶
我们可以用它来解锁机械传送带
最后 为了完成蒸汽时代 我们快速合成了第一个电路板
我们将用第一个电路板来做一个简易电解机
当然 它会电解水（更准确地说 是盐水）来获取氢氧化钠
我猜剩下的气体被排出去了
总之 我们清洗了一些铝土矿
然后把它和氢氧化钠混合提取氢氧化铝
我们用岩浆的热量来烧它 得到氧化铝
但是要从那里面提取铝 我们还需要一些冰晶石
这又要多几步化学反应
快速做完这些事情之后 我们准备好炼制第一块铝锭了
走到这一步像是完成了一个 GT 电压
现在我们正在兴头上 不想回到 RF 机械
所以我们在研究更复杂的热力发生器
因为用常规方式完成研究需要太多昂贵的方块
我们选择用昂贵但容易找到的煤来驱动研究
好了 这就是我们的二级发生器
升级内容包含一个流体缸
我们可以加入蒸汽来扩大范围 并加热我们的水来驱动导热管
有了额外的热量 我们要做的第一件事就是给蒸汽充能器供能
来给新的加热背心充能
穿上那东西 即便是暴风雪也拦不住我们
在整晚喝着热饮到处闲逛之后 我们需要的就是一个热桑拿
那给了我们很多灵感 多到我们意识到
与其像那样浪费蒸汽 不如把它输入到（紧凑型蒸汽引擎？）里
我们可以用它实现农场的自给自足
还能有更多剩余的燃料给车间用
现在车间配备了卷板机 可以做板 杆和导线
现在我们可以做一大批电路板和马达了
我们有了马达 有了电路板 有了伺服核心
这意味着我们现在可以解锁很多新机器了
然而 随着这些升级 我们的工厂已经抵达了当前冒险的终点
但别担心 等新材料和发电机发布的时候我们会回来的
拜拜